A Guide to the Dan H. Pletta Papers, 1958-1994
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Dan H. Pletta Papers, 1958-1994
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms82-006
16 boxes; 16 cu. ft.
Pletta, Dan H.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The first accession was given to Special Collections by Dan H. Pletta, Blacksburg, Virginia in 1982. The second accession was received from the Department of Engineering Science and Mechanics at Virginia Tech in 1996.
Biographical Note
Dan H. Pletta was educated at University of Illinois (B.S., 1927; C.E., 1938) and University of Wisconsin (M.S., 1931) with additional graduate study at Columbia. He was professor of Engineering Science and Mechanics at Virginia Tech (1932-72) and department head from 1958-70. As department head he guided the development of that department until it emerged as a leader in related graduate study and research. He was one of the original five University Distinguished Professors appointed in 1970 and Professor Emeritus upon his retirement in 1972. Besides teaching, his experience included design and construction in civil engineering, consulting as a stress analyst, and World War II service as an Ordinance Officer and as an instructor at the U. S. Military Academy.
Pletta's awards include an Engineering News Record Citation for Service to the construction industry, Engineer-of-the-Year Award of the Virginia Society of Professsional Engineers, and Alumni Honor Award for Distinguished Service from the College of Engineering at the University of Illinois. In1987 he received the Distinguished Service Award of the National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE). In 1988 Virginia Tech awarded him its Ruffner Medal for notable and distinguished service ot the university, and the American Society for Engineering Education (ASEE) Mechanics Division conferred its distinguished educator award on him.
He served on the National Boards of Direction of the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) and of the NSPE; as president of their Virginia affiliates; and on many committees of these and other engineering societies. He was chairman of the ASCE Committee on Professional Conduct charged with enforcing its Code of Ethics. He was chairman of the Professional Engineers in Education Practice Division and vice president of NSPE in 1977-78. He was chairman (1982-85) of the NSPE Public Advisory Review Board which serves as the Society's ombudsman for its members when disputed issues involve health and safety. Hewas honorary member of the ASCE and founding member of the American Academy of Mechanics.
Pletta was author of Engineering Statics and Dynamics (Ronald Press, 1951), Engineering Mechanics, Part I Statics, Part II Dynamics (Ronald Press, 1964), The Engineering Profession: Its Heritage and Its Emerging Purpose (1984) and numerous articles in technical journals (1952-82).
Scope and Content
Collection includes treatises, transcripts of talks and correspondence dealing with all aspects of the field of engineering, but especially with the role of education in producing a professional engineer, qualifications for practice, the public purpose of engineering, ethics, and whistleblowing. Other topics include the Department of Engineering at Virginia Tech, the American Society of Civil Engineers, National Society of Professional Engineers, the Virginia Society of Professional Engineers, and the Order of Engineers.
Arrangement
The original order in which Dan H. Pletta arranged the file folders was retained. The original file folder titles also were retained. This order is not always either choronological or alphabetical.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Local Subjects:
Faculty; Science and Technology; University Archives
Contents List
- Box 1,1942-1977, n.d.
  - University of Illinois Alumni Award, April 23, 1976. (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Personal - Miscellaneous News Items. (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Personal - Miscellaneous News Items. (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Personal - Miscellaneous News Items. (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Personal - Miscellaneous News Items. (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Personal - Congratulatory Letters, Miscellaneous Career Correspondence. (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Personal - Congratulatory Letters, Miscellaneous Career Correspondence. (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Personal - Résumé's, Photos, Who's Who, etc. (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Lab Manual, 1962-1964. (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Personal N.Y. State License. (Box-folder 1-10)
  - International Executive Service Corps. (Box-folder 1-11)
  - Engineering News, Record Citation, February 19, 1972. (Box-folder 1-12)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) Honorary Membership. (Box-folder 1-13)
  - Pletta - Army Personnel File, Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1942-1948. (Box-folder 1-14)
  - Engineer Science Mechanics (ESM) 201 vs. Physics (PHY) 217 - Teplitz Letter. (Box-folder 1-15)
  - Ethics Course - University of Maryland, New Combination--DeClans, VPI Center for Study of Science for Society. (Box-folder 1-16)
  - Miscellaneous TV Programs. (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Unions. (Box-folder 1-18)
  - Air Pollution Proposal. (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Center for Civilian Leadership. (Box-folder 1-20)
  - Lavery, William - President, Wilson, John - Provost. (Box-folder 1-21)
  - Torgersen, Paul - Dean. (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Ronald Press Corporation/ Engineering Static & Dynamic, 1951 Engineering Mechanics 1954. (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Ronald Press Corporation/ Engineering Static & Dynamic, 1951 Engineering Mechanics 1954. (Box-folder 1-24)
  - VPI Safety Engineer. (Box-folder 1-25)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box-folder 1-26)
  - Cornell University--S. C. Hollister, Walter Lynn, Richard N. White. (Box-folder 1-27)
  - Alpern, Milton. (Box-folder 1-28)
  - Billington, D. P. - Princeton University. (Box-folder 1-29)
  - Clark, Bruce Gem. (Box-folder 1-30)
  - Cochran, David. (Box-folder 1-31)
  - Angel, Pierce T. (Box-folder 1-32)
  - Congressman. (Box-folder 1-33)
  - Dillard, Joseph K., IEEE. (Box-folder 1-34)
  - Elden, Walter L. (Box-folder 1-35)
  - Galbiati, Louis J. - SUNY College of Tech. (Box-folder 1-36)
  - Goldsmith, John M. - Radford Attorney. (Box-folder 1-37)
  - Emory Johnson - South Dakota State University. (Box-folder 1-38)
  - Guy, Louis L. (Box-folder 1-39)
  - Lohmann, L.R. (Pete). (Box-folder 1-40)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1970-1977. (Box-folder 1-41)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1970-1977. (Box-folder 1-42)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1970-1977. (Box-folder 1-43)
  - Marlowe, Donald E. American Society for Engineering Education. (Box-folder 1-44)
  - McKetta, John. (Box-folder 1-45)
  - Porter, Sylvia. (Box-folder 1-46)
  - Rives, James. (Box-folder 1-47)
  - Rosenstein, Allen - National Foundation for the Professions. (Box-folder 1-48)
  - Sinclair, George. (Box-folder 1-49)
  - Staub, Susan Concerned Educators Against Forced Unionim (CEAFU). (Box-folder 1-50)
  - Tribus, Myron. (Box-folder 1-51)
  - Williamson, Merritt - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE). (Box-folder 1-52)
  - Winter, J. Ronald - Eastman Kodak. (Box-folder 1-53)
- Box 2, 1956-1980, n.d.
  - Virginia Society of Professional Engineers (VSPE) Board of Direction, 1956-1957. (Box-folder 2-54)
  - VSPE, 1956-1957. (Box-folder 2-55)
  - VSPE Charlottesville Meetings; Faculty Collective Bargaining; Virginia Tech Professional Schools Implementation Committee Report, 1974. (Box-folder 2-56)
  - VSPE Constitutions and By-Laws Committee. (Box-folder 2-57)
  - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE) State Press Conference. (Box-folder 2-58)
  - NSPE Resolution 77-17, PAO, 1980. (Box-folder 2-59)
  - New Mexico Society of Professional Engineers - Presidents File. (Box-folder 2-60)
  - NSPE Executive Committee - Minutes & Instruction. (Box-folder 2-61)
  - NSPE Board of Ethical Review. (Box-folder 2-62)
  - NSPE Engineer's Public Affairs Forum, 1977. (Box-folder 2-63)
  - NSPE Anti Trust Case. (Box-folder 2-64)
  - VSPE Membership. (Box-folder 2-65)
  - VSPE Southwestern Chapter Constitutions & Bylaws. (Box-folder 2-66)
  - VSPE Professional School Task Force, 1979. (Box-folder 2-67)
  - NSPE National Directors, 1958-1966. (Box-folder 2-68)
  - VSPE - PEE. (Box-folder 2-69)
  - VSPE - License Law Exemptions in Florida & Virginia, 1976-1977. (Box-folder 2-70)
  - VSPE Legislative Committee, 1976. (Box-folder 2-71)
  - VSPE Ethics & Practices Committee. (Box-folder 2-72)
  - VSPE Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1967-1969. (Box-folder 2-73)
  - VSPE Correspondence, 1965-1980. (Box-folder 2-74)
  - VSPE Correspondence, 1963-1964. (Box-folder 2-75)
  - VSPE Correspondence, 1965-1980. (Box-folder 2-76)
  - VSPE Correspondence, 1959-1963. (Box-folder 2-77)
  - NSPE Educational Foundation Board Minutes, 1961-1970. (Box-folder 2-78)
  - NSPE Educational Foundation National Selecting Committee, 1967-1969. (Box-folder 2-79)
  - NSPE Educational Foundation Report to NSPE Board, 1958-1973. (Box-folder 2-80)
  - NSPE Educational Committee Correspondence, 1957-1970. (Box-folder 2-81)
  - NSPE Educational Committee Correspondence, 1957-1970. (Box-folder 2-82)
  - NSPE Educational Committee Correspondence, 1977-1978. (Box-folder 2-83)
  - NSPE Educational Committee Correspondence, 1977-1978. (Box-folder 2-84)
  - NSPE Educational Committee Correspondence, 1977-1978. (Box-folder 2-85)
  - NSPE Educational Committee Report to NSPE Board. (Box-folder 2-86)
  - NSPE Educational Committee PEE Liaison, 1977-1978. (Box-folder 2-87)
  - NSPE Programs - PCAC Division - Conference on Continuing Professional Development, St Louis, July 1878. (Box-folder 2-88)
  - NSPE Professional Engineer Magazine. (Box-folder 2-89)
- Box 3, 1962-1978, n.d.
  - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE)- Registration & Qualification for Practice Committee (RQPC) Correspondence. (Box-folder 3-90)
  - NSPE- RQPC Correspondence. (Box-folder 3-91)
  - NSPE- RQPC Correspondence. (Box-folder 3-92)
  - NSPE- RQPC Agendas of Meetings. (Box-folder 3-93)
  - NSPE- RQPC Minutes. (Box-folder 3-94)
  - NSPE- RQPC. (Box-folder 3-95)
  - NSPE-RQPC "Quality for Practice & Leadership of Engineering Professionals," Development file. (Box-folder 3-96)
  - NSPE Division Minutes, PEC, PEI, PEG, PEPP. (Box-folder 3-97)
  - NSPE Division Minutes, PEC, PEI, PEG, PEPP. (Box-folder 3-98)
  - National Council of Engineering Examiners - National Evaluation System Survey. (Box-folder 3-99)
  - Engineering Foundation Conference on Life Span of Structures, 1975. (Box-folder 3-100)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) Research Council of Performance of Structures, Correspondence to, December 1975. (Box-folder 3-101)
  - ASCE Research Council of Performance of Structures, Correspondence to, December 1975. (Box-folder 3-102)
  - ASCE Research Council of Performance of Structures Correspondence, January 1978 to 1994. (Box-folder 3-103)
  - ASCE Research Council of Performance of Structures Correspondence, January 1978 to 1994. (Box-folder 3-104)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box-folder 3-105)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box-folder 3-106)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Box-folder 3-107)
  - ASCE-Virginia Section Board Minutes and Correspondence, 1962-1974. (Box-folder 3-108)
  - ASCE-Virginia Section Board Minutes and Correspondence, 1962-1974. (Box-folder 3-109)
  - ASCE-Virginia Section Correspondence and Newsletter, 1962-1974. (Box-folder 3-110)
  - ASCE-Virginia Section 50th Anniversary Public Communication. (Box-folder 3-111)
  - ASCE-Virginia Section Goals Committee. (Box-folder 3-112)
  - ASCE-Virginia Section Miscellaneous Projects, 1966-1972. (Box-folder 3-113)
  - ASCE-Virginia Section Newsletters and Correspondence, 1966-1967. (Box-folder 3-114)
  - ASCE-Virginia Section Resolution of Appointment of Deans. (Box-folder 3-115)
  - ASCE-Miscellaneous- Committee on Professional Practice, 1969-1970. (Box-folder 3-116)
  - ASCE-Miscellaneous- Committee on Registration of Engineers, 1970. (Box-folder 3-117)
  - ASCE-Miscellaneous- Committee of Society Prizes. (Box-folder 3-118)
  - ASCE-Miscellaneous- COSOPO- " Goals for ASCE" report, 1973. (Box-folder 3-119)
- Box 4, 1966-1979, n.d.
  - American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE)-Miscellaneous- Local Sections' Conferences (Box-folder 4-120)
  - ASCE-Ethics Conference Abstracts and Papers. (Box-folder 4-121)
  - ASCE-Ethics Conference Correspondence. (Box-folder 4-122)
  - ASCE-Ethics Conference Invited Speakers. (Box-folder 4-123)
  - ASCE-Ethics Conference Minutes. (Box-folder 4-124)
  - ASCE-Ethics Conference Memos. (Box-folder 4-125)
  - ASCE-Ethics Conference Memos. (Box-folder 4-126)
  - ASCE-Ethics Conference Memos. (Box-folder 4-127)
  - ASCE-Ethics - Arizona Summons. (Box-folder 4-128)
  - ASCE-Ethics Confidential Ethics Advisory Service. (Box-folder 4-129)
  - ASCE-CPC Advertising. (Box-folder 4-130)
  - ASCE-CPC Case Studies. (Box-folder 4-131)
  - ASCE-CPC Code Revision. (Box-folder 4-132)
  - ASCE-CPC Correspondence. (Box-folder 4-133)
  - ASCE-CPC News Items. (Box-folder 4-134)
  - ASCE-CPC News Items continued. (Box-folder 4-135)
  - ASCE-CPC Procedures for Professional Conduct - Internal Rules of Policy and Procedure CPC Handbook. (Box-folder 4-136)
  - Sidney Siskin's Project - Cornell Ethics Course. (Box-folder 4-137)
  - Professional Engineers in Education (PEE) Correspondence, June 1974 - June 1976. (Box-folder 4-138)
  - PEE Committee Reassessment of Engineering and Engineering Technology (REETS). (Box-folder 4-139)
  - PEE Correspondence - data, November 1977. (Box-folder 4-140)
  - PEE Correspondence, June 1976 - November 1977. (Box-folder 4-141)
  - PEE Miscellaneous Memos, 1977-1978. (Box-folder 4-142)
  - PEE News Items. (Box-folder 4-143)
  - PEE Correspondence. (Box-folder 4-144)
  - PEE Correspondence. (Box-folder 4-145)
  - PEE Newsletter, 1966-1975. (Box-folder 4-146)
  - PEE Budget. (Box-folder 4-147)
  - PEE Correspondence. (Box-folder 4-148)
  - PEE Rules of Government and Operation. (Box-folder 4-149)
  - PEE Organization - Board of Governors Meeting, New Orleans, January 1978. (Box-folder 4-150)
  - PEE Correspondence. (Box-folder 4-151)
  - PEE Organization - Board of Governors Meeting, St. Louis, July 1978. (Box-folder 4-152)
  - PEE Organization - Board of Governors Meeting, Atlanta, January 1979. (Box-folder 4-153)
  - ASCE. (Box-folder 4-154)
  - PEE Committee Financing Engineering Education. (Box-folder 4-155)
  - PEE Committee on Continuing Professional Development. (Box-folder 4-156)
- Box 5, 1950-1979, n.d.
  - Professional Engineers in Education (PEE) Committee on Ethics Text. (Box-folder 5-157)
  - PEE Committee- Engineering Manpower. (Box-folder 5-158)
  - PEE Committee- Campus Collective Bargain. (Box-folder 5-159)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) National District 6 - Council: Correspondence. (Box-folder 5-160)
  - ASCE National District 6 - Director Correspondence. (Box-folder 5-161)
  - ASCE National Committee on Society Objectives, Planning and Organization (COSOPO) Goals Report, 1973. (Box-folder 5-162)
  - ASCE National District 6 - Council, 1964-1970. (Box-folder 5-163)
  - ASCE Nominees. (Box-folder 5-164)
  - ASCE National Committee on Registration of Engineers, 1969. (Box-folder 5-165)
  - ASCE Article " Social Science Emphasis in Engineer Education," New Orleans, April 16, 1975. (Box-folder 5-166)
  - PEE Executive Board Meeting, Atlanta, March 1979. (Box-folder 5-167)
  - PEE Executive Board Meeting, Chicago, September 1978. (Box-folder 5-168)
  - PEE Executive Board Meeting, St. Louis, November 1978. (Box-folder 5-169)
  - PEE Organization. Minutes of Board of Governors and Executive Board. (Box-folder 5-170)
  - PEE Organization - Report to NSPE Board. (Box-folder 5-171)
  - PEE Workshop " Engineer Education and College Bargain," Kansas City, 1976. (Box-folder 5-172)
  - PEE Workshop- Leadership and Profession, St. Louis, November 1977. (Box-folder 5-173)
  - PEE Workshop - Profession and Code Enforcement, New Orleans, 1979. (Box-folder 5-174)
  - Education Reports- Petition to Southern regional Educational Board, 1950. (Box-folder 5-175)
  - Education Reports- Virginia State Council of Higher Education Correspondence and Minutes, 1954-1959. (Box-folder 5-176)
  - VPI Conferences - Graduate Summer Session, 1950. (Box-folder 5-177)
  - VPI Conferences - Graduate Summer Session, 1950. (Box-folder 5-178)
  - VPI Conferences - 1961 NASA Conference- Miscellaneous Correspondence and Attendance. (Box-folder 5-179)
  - New Development in Engineer Design, 1954. (Box-folder 5-180)
  - VPI Conference - National Science Foundation (NSF) Engineer Profession- Its Public Purpose, 1972. (Box-folder 5-181)
  - VPI Conference- VPI-ESM Interface conferences, 1969-1970. (Box-folder 5-182)
  - Miscellaneous Article " The Engineer Profession & Its Public Purpose," January 26, 1977. (Box-folder 5-183)
  - Miscellaneous Articles. (Box-folder 5-184)
  - ASCE Article- ASCE's Constructive Influence on Education, 1971. (Box-folder 5-185)
  - ASCE Article -ASCE's Public Policy & Organization, 1964. (Box-folder 5-186)
  - VPI Research Project 256 - Reinforced Concrete Research Council, 1951-1958. (Box-folder 5-187)
  - ASCE Article "Making of a Professional." (Box-folder 5-188)
  - ASCE Article "Engineer Diplomats- Public Advocates Worldwide," 1976. (Box-folder 5-189)
- Box 6, 1975-1982, n.d.
  - American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE) Article" Ethical Codes- Enforcement vs. Obedience" Baltimore Conference, 1975. (Box-folder 6-190)
  - ASCE Article "Engineering Profession- A Light at the End of the Tunnel," 1975. (Box-folder 6-191)
  - ASCE Article "Engineering Leadership & Teamwork- Preserve of Free Enterprise." (Box-folder 6-192)
  - ASCE Article "Engineering - Answers for the 1980's" Student Chapter Conference, March 7, 1980. (Box-folder 6-193)
  - ASCE Article "Educating Engineers for Professional and Ethical Responsibility," 1975; "Beyond Whistle Blowing: Defining Engineering Responsibilities." (Box-folder 6-194)
  - ASCE Article "Are We Educating Engineer Professionals?" 1980. (Box-folder 6-195)
  - ASCE Article "Tomorrows Professional Engineers- The Public's Advocate," 1976. (Box-folder 6-196)
  - ASCE Article "Ut Prosimus et Duedmus" "Trends in Faculty Quality and Objectives." (Box-folder 6-197)
  - "Why Professional Schools for Engineers?" 1979. (Box-folder 6-198)
  - ASCE Article "Consulting and Licensing of Engineering Facilities," 1976. (Box-folder 6-199)
  - ASCE Article "To Practice or Perish." (Box-folder 6-200)
  - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE) Article "Emerging Professional Schools of Engineering" ASEE talk, June 24, 1971. (Box-folder 6-201)
  - ASCE Article "New Education Environment for Tomorrows PE" Florida, 1978. (Box-folder 6-202)
  - ASCE Article/Encouraging Professional Development with Engineering Specialty Board, Diplomats and Unity. (Box-folder 6-203)
  - American Society for Engineering Education Article "Source, Founding and Destination of Graduate Studies in Mechanics." (Box-folder 6-204)
  - American Society for Engineering Education Article "Today's Challenge to Engineers - Lead or Be Led." (Box-folder 6-205)
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) Article- Discussion- Victor Parschiks' Paper. (Box-folder 6-206)
  - American Society for Engineering Education - State Board Regulation of Engineers--"Special Task Report." (Box-folder 6-207)
  - ASME Article "Personally Speaking." (Box-folder 6-208)
  - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE) Article "Collective Bargaining and Engineering Facility"; PE Jan 1976, "Faculty Unions? A Profession? What shall we respond?" (Box-folder 6-209)
  - NSPE Article " Coupling Economics with Ethics for Employed Engineers," 1977. (Box-folder 6-210)
  - "The Development of Professional Schools." (Box-folder 6-211)
  - NSPE Article "Guest Comment" April 1978; "Readers Forum" August 1978 (Box-folder 6-212)
  - NSPE Article " Professional Unity, Unionism, Unitization and Reunion." (Box-folder 6-213)
  - NSPE Article "Pressures in Engineering Education" PE, February 1973. (Box-folder 6-214)
  - NSPE Workshops St. Louis 1977; Kansas City 1976. (Box-folder 6-215)
  - Tennessee Valley Engineer "The Engineer - His Brothers' Keepers," 1971. (Box-folder 6-216)
  - Virginia Society if Professional engineers- "When is Engineering Registration Required?" (Box-folder 6-217)
  - Virginia Engineers 1973 - "Unionized Faculties." (Box-folder 6-218)
  - Torch Magazine "Professionalism Demands on Added Dimension." (Box-folder 6-219)
  - Blacksburg Sun "Apostrophe." (Box-folder 6-220)
  - Miscellaneous Papers- "All Nailed Lumber--Truss Fatigue Life of AIS1 Steel." (Box-folder 6-221)
  - Patents -Laws - Robert J. Kuntz. (Box-folder 6-222)
  - Miscellaneous Talks - Georgia Institute Of Technology, 1976. (Box-folder 6-223)
  - Miscellaneous Talks - McDonald Douglas 1979 - San Diego State University 1979. (Box-folder 6-224)
  - Miscellaneous Talks- National Conference on technology - Purdue 1978 "Technology Spectrum Interface," October 16, 1978. (Box-folder 6-225)
  - Miscellaneous Talks - University of Alabama, October 25-26, 1979. (Box-folder 6-226)
  - Miscellaneous Talks--Virginia, West Virginia. (Box-folder 6-227)
  - NSPE State Society Talks, Texas, June 1977. (Box-folder 6-228)
  - NSPE State Society Talks Pennsylvania, 1977-1980. (Box-folder 6-229)
  - NSPE State Society Talks - Indiana, March 16, 1977. (Box-folder 6-230)
  - NSPE State Society Talks Massachusetts, April 28, 1977. (Box-folder 6-231)
  - Miscellaneous Talks - University of Kansas, March 26, 1982. (Box-folder 6-232)
  - Miscellaneous Talks - AIAA Connecticut Section. (Box-folder 6-233)
  - Miscellaneous Talks - Rennslaer- NSF Ethics Conference, May 1982. (Box-folder 6-234)
  - Professional Schools - Criteria, VPI. (Box-folder 6-235)
  - Professional Schools VPI - Memos to Dean. (Box-folder 6-236)
  - Professional Schools VPI - College Reorganization. (Box-folder 6-237)
  - Professional Schools - VPI Task Force, November 1972. (Box-folder 6-238)
  - Professional Schools - VPI Report, 1972. (Box-folder 6-239)
  - Professional Schools - VPI Report, 1972. (Box-folder 6-240)
  - Professional Schools - VPI Final Report. (Box-folder 6-241)
  - Professional Schools - VPI Final Report. (Box-folder 6-242)
  - Professional Schools - VPI Final Report. (Box-folder 6-243)
  - VPI Engineering Technology Phase Out, 1977. (Box-folder 6-244)
- Box 7, 1972-1983, n.d.
  - Professional Schools Miscellaneous - Florida Professional Schools Act. (Box-folder 7-245)
  - Professional Schools Miscellaneous - Matheny Correspondence, 1977-1979. (Box-folder 7-246)
  - Professional Schools Miscellaneous - Matheny Correspondence, 1977-1979. (Box-folder 7-247)
  - Professional Schools Miscellaneous - Matheny Correspondence, 1977-1979. (Box-folder 7-248)
  - Professional Schools Miscellaneous - Matheny Correspondence #2, 1980-1982. (Box-folder 7-249)
  - Professional Schools Miscellaneous - Matheny Correspondence #2, 1980-1982. (Box-folder 7-250)
  - Professional Schools Miscellaneous - Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 7-251)
  - Professional Schools - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE)--Criteria. (Box-folder 7-252)
  - Professional Schools - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE)- President Nicholas Correspondence. (Box-folder 7-253)
  - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE) - Professional Schools Task Force. (Box-folder 7-254)
  - Professional Schools - NSPE/PEE - Long Range Strategy Memo Comments. (Box-folder 7-255)
  - Professional Schools - NSPE/PEE - Long Range Strategy Memo Responses. (Box-folder 7-256)
  - USA Regional Advisory Panel. (Box-folder 7-257)